Guide to the Isaac Russell Papers, 1898-1927
Department of Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE, ca. 1909-1925
  - Sinclair, Upton, Feb. 1919-Sept. 1925 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Sinnot-Smith, J. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Smith, Joseph F., Apr. 1911-Aug. 1913 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Smith, Joseph F., Nov. 1913-June 1918, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Smith, M.-Smoot (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Solomon-Speilberg (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Stanford University-Stromberg Brothers (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Strother-Sullivan, M. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Sullivan, Mark, Jan. 1907-Oct. 1912 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Sullivan, Mark, Dec. 1912-May 1926 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Sullivan. P.-Symonds (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Taggart-Talmage (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Tannenbaum-Thomas, G. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Thomas, George, May 1922-June 1922 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Thomas, George, July 1922-Mar. 1926, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Thompson, John, Mar. 1909-Dec. 1909 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Thompson, John, June 1911-Dec. 1914. n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Thomson-Trask (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Treganza-Tumulty (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ude-United States Railroad Commission (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - United States Weather Bureau-Vroman (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Wade-Walsh (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - War Department-Ward. G. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ward, Ralph R., Feb. 1921-May 1922 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Ward, Ralph R., June 1922-Mar. 1923 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ward, Ralph R., Apr. 1923-Aug. 1925 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Ward Baking Company-Wells (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - West-Wheeler (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - White-Whitney (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Whittlesey (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Widtsoe, John A., Mar. 1913-Oct. 1920 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Widtsoe, John A., Dec. 1921-July 1922 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Widtsoe, John A., Sept. 1922-Aug. 1923 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Widtsoe, John A., Sept. 1923-May 1927 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Wilbur (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Wiley-Wisconsin Highway Commission (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Wisconsin Legislature-Wood, L. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Wood, Richard S., June 1920-June 1922 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Wood, Richard S., June 1922-Dec. 1922 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Woodruff (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Woods (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Wooley-Wyckoff Yellow Taxicab-Young (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Unidentified fragments, from Isaac Russell (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified fragments, from Isaac Russell (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified fragments, from Isaac Russell (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified fragments, to Isaac Russell (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Isaac Russell with indecipherable signatures (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Isaac Russell with no, or incomplete signatures (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Isaac Russell with no, or incomplete signatures (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Isaac Russell with unidentified surnames of recipients (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda (Box 9, Folder 9)
- WRITINGS, ca. 1905-1927
  - MAJOR WORKS
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch. 1, 13-14 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch. 16-18 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch 19-21 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch. 22-24 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch. 25-27 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch. 27a-29 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1, Ch. 30-33 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1,[no chapter numbers] (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 1 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 1-4 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 6, 8, 14 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 15-18 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 15-18 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 10-22 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 23-25 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 2, Ch. 26-29 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 1-4 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 6-9 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 10-12 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 14-16 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 16a-19 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 20-23 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 24-26 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3, Ch. 26a-27 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3,[no chapter numbers] (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 3 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 1-4 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 5-7 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 8-10 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 11-13 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 14-16 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 17-18. 20 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 21-23 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 24-26 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 27-29 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch - 30-31, 33 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 34-35 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 36-38 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Hidden Heroes manuscript no. 4, Ch. 39-40 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 5, Ch. 1 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 5, Ch. 2-5 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 5, Ch. 6-9 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 5, Ch. 10-12 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 5, Ch. 15-27 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Hidden Heroes, manuscript no. 6, Ch. 12-13, 19 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Hidden Heroes, fragments (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Hidden Heroes, research notes (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Hidden Heroes, research notes (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Hidden Heroes, research notes (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Hidden Heroes, quoted extracts (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Hidden Heroes, quoted extracts (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Hidden Heroes, quoted extracts (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Hidden Heroes, quoted extracts (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Hidden Heroes, quoted extracts (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Hidden Heroes, reviews and comments (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Holes in Bread, manuscript, pp. 1-24 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Holes in Bread, manuscript, pp. 25-45 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Holes in Bread, manuscript, pp. 46-70 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Holes in Bread, manuscript, pp. 71-97 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Holes in Bread, reviews and comments (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 1 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 2-3 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 4-5 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 6-7 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 8-10 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 11-13 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 14-16 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 17-18 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 19-20 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 21-23 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Greenwich Village, Ch. 24-25 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - NEWSPAPERS AND JOURNAL ARTICLES
    - "Cold Charity" (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Daniel Webster" (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "Days of Man", review (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "Gyp" (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "How Lt. Col. Philip St. George Cooke ... Helped the Utah Pioneers" (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "If the Little Hawks..." (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "An Important Utah Diary" (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "In re Yoshke Nigger" (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Jailed" (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "John Jacob Astor..." (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "Joseph Smith..." (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "La Sal" (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "The Last Christmas Feed" (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - "The Late George F. Ruxton" (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "Like to be Thought a Liar?" (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "A Little Gould Baby" (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "A Little Mountain Town" (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - "Lowbrowing the Highbrows at the Movies" (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - "Must the New be Always Swatted?" (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - "The Old New in Your Daily Bread" (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - "On Charity's Fight Against Widows" (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "Out on the Air" (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "The Plight of Frank P. Walsh" (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - "Power" (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "Regarding Jefferson and Roosevelt" (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - "The Rise of Anthony Jay" (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - "Robert E. Ward" (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "The Salaried Class" (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - "A Short Story" (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "Tales of the Old Townsend House" (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - "They Slapped Him Down in Paris..." (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - "Trappers. Pioneers, and Mormon Battalion" (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - "Waiting for Armageddon" (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "What Will the Trustbusters Bust?" (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - "When a Great Utahan Adventurer..." (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - "When Kearny... Broke the Utah Trail" (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - "When Little Willie Tried to Run Away From Home" (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - "Why Beemis Flunked Out" (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - "Why I Am a 'Mormon?'" (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - "Why the Blackfeet Fought" (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - "Women and the Trusts" (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Untitled manuscripts on charity (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Untitled manuscript on farming (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Untitled manuscripts on food (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Untitled manuscripts on food (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Untitled manuscripts on "Harry Young" (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Untitled manuscripts on "Harry Young" (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Untitled manuscripts on ice distribution (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Untitled manuscripts on Indians (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Untitled manuscripts on James Parrie (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Untitled manuscripts on "Jim" (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Untitled manuscripts on labor injustices (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Untitled manuscripts on Louis Pasteur (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Unititled manuscripts on the Mormon Battalion (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Unititled manuscripts on the Mormon Battalion (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Untitled manuscripts on the Philippines (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Untitled manuscripts on reporters (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Untitled manuscripts on women (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - OTHER UNPUBLISHED WRITINGS
    - Editorials (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Fragments (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Fragments (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Research notes, on food (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Research notes, miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Research notes, miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - PUBLISHED ARTICLES
    - American Baker-Baker's Weekly (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Collier's-Goodwin's Weekly (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Improvement Era-Independent (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Masses (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Nation's Business-Nation's Health (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - New Republic-Northwestern Miller (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Oregon Merchant-Pearson's (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Progressive (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Progressive (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Progressive (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Rotarian (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - World's Work (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Unidentified (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - NEWSCLIPPINGS
    - 1905-1907 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - 1908 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - 1909 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - 1909 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - 1909 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - 1910 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - 1912 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1914 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1915 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Apr.-May 1916 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - June 1916 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - July-Aug. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Aug.-Sept. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Aug.-Sept. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Apr. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - May 1917 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - June-Aug. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - July-Aug. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Aug.-Oct. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Jan.-Mar. 1918 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Mar. 1918 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Feb.-Mar, Dec. 1918 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - 1922-1924 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - 1925 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - 1926 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1927 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Extracts from Hidden Heroes (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "Headings" only (Box 14, Folder 5)
- SUBJECT FILES, ca. 1905-1927
  - Aviation, correspondence, 1914-1924 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Aviation, correspondence, 1914-1924 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Aviation, correspondence, 1912-1914 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Aviation, manuscripts (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Aviation, manuscripts (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Aviation, manuscripts (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Aviation, manuscripts (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Aviation, newsclippings and magazine articles, 1908-1922 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Aviation, miscellany (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Baking (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Central America, correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Central America, memoranda and chronologies (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Central America, newsclippings, 1908-1910 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Central America, newsclippings, 1912-1913 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Central America, newsclippings, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Central America, miscellany (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Community Art League (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, capitalism vs. socialism, correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, capitalism vs. socialism, manuscripts (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, capitalism vs. socialism, articles (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, general (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, labor troubles, Bridgeport, 1918-1919 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, labor troubles, longshoremen, 1918-1919 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, labor troubles, Philadelphia. 1909 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, labor troubles, Pottsville, Bethlehem, Reading, 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Economic and Labor Issues, unemployment, 1914-1915 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Egypt (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Egypt (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Electricity, editorials by Isaac Russell (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Electricity, miscellany (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Farming (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Food (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Free speech and Tarrytown (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Mormonism, criticism (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Mormonism, defense (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Mormonism, history (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Mormonism, history (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Mormonism, letters by Isaac Russell to editors, 1911-1913 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Mormonism, letters by Isaac Russell to editors, 1913-1914 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Mormonism, letters by Isaac Russell to editors, 1914-1918 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Mormonism, letters by Isaac Russell to editors, 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Mormonism, polygamy, miscellaneous documents (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Mormonism, "Polygamy," a play (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Mormonism, TR and the Mormons (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Mormonism, miscellaneous newsclippings (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - New York vs. Ward (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Palisades Park (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Palisades Park (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Recruiting (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Seagull Monument, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Tacoma-Rainier dispute, correspondence, 1924-1927 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Tacoma-Rainier dispute, newsclippings and articles, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Titanic, manuscript (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Titanic, newsclippings, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Titanic, 1912-1914 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Union Pacific Railroad, correspondence, 1910-1914 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Utah, history, newsclippings, 1905-1924 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Utah, history, miscellaneous articles, 1911-1918 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Vaniman, Melvin, correspondence, 1911-1914 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Vaniman, Melvin, manuscripts (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Vaniman, Melvin, manuscripts and articles, 1911-1918 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous writings by others (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Ephemera (Box 16, Folder 14)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, 1916, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)